If you want to become better leader in India and understand all the leaders of today
then subscribe to this channel Rajshmani Clips.
So, I tell you,
what is the typical media business?
And what was wrong?
In this case, I open this opportunity here,
I do it in 42.
I think it was wrong.
So,
traditionally media before the digital age was print and TV,
fundamentally.
And print and TV,
both the setups and the distribution and the distribution cost is very high.
And it's not every day you can set up a TV station or a newspaper or a magazine.
The way to reach there is not easy.
The digital fundamentally solved this problem for everyone.
Right?
Where they said, now it's easy.
The distribution is easy.
Right? So, I think when we started,
it was not that something was wrong.
I think it did not exist.
Right?
So, in 2014-15,
one thing we knew,
we have started a ecosystem.
What tech broadly is going to be the future?
Everyone knows that now.
But we could see it in 14-15 because you study US cycles and all of that.
And you can see it here.
India may be thought,
there was a huge gap.
So,
I am a doctor.
What should I do?
It almost sounds like when we used to read,
sorry, I am a man,
a man, a man, a man, a man, a man, a man,
a man, a man,
a man,
a man, a man.
So, because you know, what is possible?
But I think the whole startup ecosystem,
the concept was everything is possible.
Can you bridge it with the larger audience in their language by solving the terms,
by breaking down everything?
That was a fundamental of why we started.
Okay.
And then we realized information,
it's a way of packaging and presenting,
which matters more than the information.
Which is better designed and the whole packaging.
So, packaging comes into the play.
So, I think for us design and packaging has been one of the key drivers of our growth.
So, copy and design.
Copy and design.
And how again, how we package part of the copy and design.
So, that has been one key factor.
And for us, I think we were very early movers.
I wouldn't call first movers.
There were a couple of companies who were doing it.
We were very early movers.
Our design, copy packaging was up to the mark which India usually has not seen.
I had a fits time.
And we had a huge belief that the content we are doing is going to become one of the key pillars.
Of the country in next time into 10 years,
which it has become now,
where startup today is part of startup 20.
Like a G20 with S20 now.
There's a prime minister talking about the startup ecosystem.
Right. With this lot of data which is needed around it,
we are raised more than 140 billion dollar as a country in startups.
More than 90,000 startups.
140 billion dollar raised 110 plus unicorns.
Right.
And again, unicorn may be a backtum or a good term right now.
But it is the index of.
Yeah.
Growth or health of the country in this context.
Right. A certain level of success.
We know and thought this in 2014 or 2015.
Right.
And under confident country suddenly gets a lot of confidence that yes,
we can also do it.
Right.
Yes, we have a talent.
We have the means and it is not as hard as we thought it will be.
And you know, the whole every model you see now is coming from those areas.
But people are just getting up and saying,
we will make it.
And we are right.
Right.
Today's space tech.
You see.
Of course, great success.
But there are too many startups right who are building rockets.
So I made a rocket.
I thought, you are making a rocket.
You made a rocket.
Well, that's not easy.
Yeah. You think that you have to make a rocket.
I mean, content money is fine.
Rocket money.
Well, such amazing talent.
Yeah.
But no one no one brought this talent together and said,
you can do it.
We will pay.
No one funded this.
No one funded that.
Right.
And it was even not possible to go out and raise money.
The opportunity did not exist right.
So for us,
the third process was,
the year in the last 10 years,
India will reach here.
World will reach here.
Can we play a role in the success of the overall country when it comes to the startup ecosystem?
Larger third process.
And then we keep kept on evolving,
evolving, evolving over the years.
And then we said,
here, if we are helping founders and investors and the operators to create impact,
we eventually become a big catalyst of overall impact.
Now, this is what I was told to do.
We have to forward this success.
This is all right.
We have to process how stories are made.
How to get from the market.
How do we know how to do it?
How do we verify it?
What is the process?
I don't know.
Just tell me.
I think, and again, I can generally say for any media company.
I tell you, I want to cut down and tell you something.
When I want to make some content related to startup,
then I go to the
YouTube,
I will go to the Forbes, the Money Control,
the InSubs, and I will read them.
And then I will make it.
Where do you guys get it from?
All the content great is very media.
And we learn from there.
So here's what I solved.
And this is what I'm solving through
figuring out as well.
It's like the same conversation that brother is coming.
Flipkart is a billion dollars.
So what do I do?
What I'm solving is that if we cut this flip,
then this will make this opportunity.
This opportunity can be taken like this.
This is what happens.
So I'm just opening it.
How do I convert it into an opportunity and explain it to people?
But my sources are you guys.
How do you get sources?
I think multiple sources are.
I think, like for us,
a lot of companies will reach out to us directly and say,
this is what they do.
Sometimes you ask them to show data or proof.
Sometimes you don't, depending on the nature of the content.
And credibility,
right? Now for your hypothetical,
you can quote a unique founder and say something.
And if he is wrong,
then you will come to the founder.
Right?
And then you also build this gut over the years.
Other journalists.
And it's not me.
Right?
I'm not even a journalist.
The folks who work,
the actual journalists who actually produce this content,
they do the hard work.
Right? So they build the gut.
Right?
Pooja, I co-found her.
She is editor in chief.
She would have.
She has a lot of gut.
And I see this every day.
And I ask her, how?
And she said, no, I said, no, I said, no, I don't want to prove it.
She said, look how it's going to look.
And like two days down,
three days down the line,
we'll, I will hear the same news.
Right? So you just get the nag on doing things.
Right? Look, people can't tell you.
They're not right.
I wish.
So that's why we're in a physiological business side.
But I think after reading the content or the,
or consuming the information,
you can start making sense.
Right?
You do figuring out you,
you see a lot of podcasts.
And you think, you need me, you can ask a number of podcasts.
You'll just launch a video and then you'll get 5 million views in one hour.
You'll say, you'll get the phone.
Or you'll say, you'll get the phone.
What's going on?
It's just like the same thing.
Right? You build that gut.
Gutt plays a very important role for any journalist.
Because you cannot ask proof of everything.
Right?
So one is companies coming to us.
Second is credible sources like founders,
investors coming on record.
Then a lot of these people come off record.
They would share a lot of information with us off the record.
Anonymous.
Malavino.
But they would share off the record for various reasons.
They don't want their name, etc.
etc. Why did they do that?
Again, they might have their own vested reasons.
They might want to do general good.
Multiple reasons.
Then it's a journalist call to see.
He has a reason.
What's going to happen to me?
And based on,
you know, if it fits the bill,
you go ahead or not go ahead.
If you see every media and specially political is branded.
Yeah, it is gang couple.
Every media belongs to a gang.
But then media doesn't know.
Everyone else knows.
If people say that you are a gang partner.
I never said that in gang meetings.
I mean, if there is a meeting meeting,
then what will happen?
Which party will you be in?
I mean, I have given money to come to a gang.
People have very interesting perceptions.
And these perceptions become Chinese vispers.
And then Chinese vispers become reality.
Right?
But actually,
there is nothing.
So, when you come to sources again,
people tell companies tell off the record on the record.
Then we get to know from network a lot.
You build this network over five years,
ten years.
People tell you a lot of things.
Then a lot of employees in the company,
when they are getting fired.
Or something goes wrong.
They want to come on record.
They want to come off record and tell you.
So you eventually build a network and get plays a very important role.
And then comes to your thoughts.
Your brand thoughts, your internal thoughts as an individual as a journalist.
What you will write,
what you will not write.
Thank you so much for watching this clip till the end.
Please subscribe to get more insightful clips,
which will help you become a better leader.